（麦迪逊公园酒店）
好可爱 等等 她来了
That's cute. Oh, wait. Oh, she's here.
嘿 姑娘
Hey, girl.
-你终于来了 -我来了
-You made it, finally. -I did.
嗨
Hey.
-你好漂亮 -来认识一下我姐姐
-Oh, you look so cute. -Oh, come meet my sister.
-嗨 -嗨 幸会
-Hey. -Hi. Nice to meet you.
见到你真高兴
So lovely to meet you.
糟糕 我希望那不…
I hope it wasn't--
-请享用 -谢谢
-There you go. -Thanks.
（根据电视剧集《假旗行动》改编）
（主创：阿米特科恩、玛丽亚费尔德曼）
（格林威治时间 晚上7点58分）
（伦敦市 主教门警察局）
乔普拉先生 你涉嫌串谋劫持而被捕
Mr. Chopra, you've been arrested on suspicion of conspiracy to abduct.
本次谈话将进行录音和录像
This interview will be recorded with both video and audio.
我必须提醒你 你什么都不必说
I have to remind you that you don't have to say anything,
但若在接受讯问时隐瞒了信息 而将来在法庭上
but it may harm your defense if you do not mention when questioned
你要依靠这些信息 这可能对你的辩护不利
something which you later rely on in court.
你所说的一切可能被用作证据
Anything you do say may be given in evidence.
我知道已经问过你了 不过为了录像再问你一次
I know you've already been asked, but for the sake of the camera,
你确定你不需要有律师在场吗
are you sure you don't want legal representation?
我不需要 显然是某种误会
I don't need it. There's obviously been some sort of misunderstanding.
我们走着瞧吧
Well, we'll see.
我会对你实话实说 希望你也能这样
I'm gonna be honest with you in the hope that you'll reciprocate.
没时间玩游戏
No time for games.
我们有理由相信 一个年轻人的生命危在旦夕
We have reason to believe a young man's life is at risk.
如实回答我的问题 我会帮助你
Answer my questions honestly, and I'll help you.
如果对我说谎 我就无能无力了
Lie to me, and I won't be able to.
里奥纽曼在哪里
Where is Leo Newman?
-我一无所知 -这是认真的吗
-I have absolutely no idea. -Is this for real?
他在英国境内吗
Is he here in the UK?
这不是什夫的恶作剧
This isn't Shiv winding me up?
是 我是说 无可奉告
Yeah, I mean, no comment.
哪个里奥
Leo who?
你认识这个吗
Do you recognize this?
里奥自从被塞进那个行李箱后 没有人见过他或听到他的消息
Leo hasn't been seen or heard of since being bundled into that suitcase.
这些面具有什么意义
What's the significance of the masks?
我不知道 我从来没听说过里奥牛顿
I don't know. I've never even heard of Leo Newton.
纽曼
Newman.
你不可能认为是我绑架了他吧
Can't seriously think I kidnapped him.
劫持只有在收到赎金要求或活着的证明时
Abduction is only classified as kidnap once a ransom demand
才被归类为绑架
or proof of life has been received.
在知道戴面具者想要什么之前
Until we know what the people in the masks want,
我们无法确定这是否与恐怖分子有关
we can't be certain whether this is terrorist-related,
是否有政治动机或就是简单的敲诈勒索
politically motivated or simple extortion.
-你在问我吗  -你知道吗
-Are you asking me? -Do you know?
你认为我蠢到没有律师在场 坐在这里回答问题
Do you think I'd be stupid enough to do this without a solicitor
如果我参与其中的话
if I was involved?
这也同样可以被理解为你很聪明
Well, it could equally be construed as very smart.
我什么时候能离开这里
When can I get out of here?
我妈妈要急疯了
My mum is gonna be in a right state.
回答问题 帮助说服
Answer the questions, help convince
我们的美国朋友 你只不过是一名财务经理
our American friends you're nothing more than a finance manager
碰上了倒霉的一天
having a really bad day,
我们几小时之内就能让你离开 好吗
and we'll get you out of here in a matter of hours, okay?
“好吗”
"Okay"?
为了今天我准备了两年
Today took two years to plan.
人们从世界各地赶来 花了超出预算的钱
People came from all over the world, spent money they haven't got.
所以不 实际上我现在的状况 跟“好”差了十万八千里
So, no. Actually, I'm about as far from "okay" as I could possibly be right now.
来吧
Come on.
问你的问题吧
Ask your questions,
然后我会咨询我的未婚夫 他碰巧是一名律师
and then I'll consult my fiancé, who happens to be a lawyer,
你到底得花多少钱 才能让这事“好”起来
about exactly how much it's gonna cost you to make this anything like "okay."
你认识这个人吗
Do you know this man?
从来没见过
Never seen him before.
无可奉告
No comment.
他是谁
Who is he?
你知道他现在可能在哪里吗
Do you have any idea where he might be now?
（北爱尔兰 班戈）
肖恩
Seany?
你好 爷爷
Hello, Granda.
肖恩
Son.
告诉我从你到达美国那一刻所有的行踪
Give me a full account from the time you arrived in America.
我从机场搭德士到酒店和我妹妹见面
I got a cab from the airport and met my sister at the hotel.
-莫妮克  -她在上纽约大学
-Monique? -She's at NYU.
我从来没去过 所以计划晚上出去玩
I've never been over, so the plan was to have a night out,
算是告别单身派对吧 然后带她一起回来
sort of hen party, and then bring her back.
-她也在这里吗  -请继续
-Is she here too? -Keep going, please.
房间还没准备好 所以我们就去参观了一些景点
The room wasn't ready yet, so we went and saw some sights.
买了些东西 然后莫妮回了她自己的住处
Did some shopping, and then Mon went back to her place.
我回了酒店
I went back to the hotel.
这是几点钟
What time was this?
大约5点
5:00-ish?
然后呢
And then?
我安排了跟莫妮7点30在一个酒吧碰头
I'd arranged to meet Mon at a bar at 7:30,
所以 我打开了行李 休息了一下
so I unpacked and chilled for a bit.
你又离开过房间吗
And did you leave again
在回到酒店和去酒吧之间
between arriving back and going to the bar?
我记得去了水疗中心
I think I went to the spa.
是 我…离开过
Yeah, I did.
不过 当我到更衣室的时候
But when I got to the changing room,
莫妮给我发短信说 我们应该在酒店喝杯鸡尾酒
Mon texted and said we should get a cocktail at the hotel
在她朋友到达之前
before her friends turned up.
你没用水疗中心就离开了
-So you left without using the spa?
对
-Yes.
你在酒店各处走动的时候 有没有遇到其他人
And did you meet anyone else as you moved around the hotel?
我收拾好然后和莫妮见面了
I got ready and met Mon.
你得去问莫妮克和她的朋友
And you'll have to speak to Monique and her friends
在那之后我们去了哪里
about where we went after that.
我只知道 有好多酒吧
All I know is, there were a lot of bars,
一个夜总会、跳舞、香槟
a club, dancing, champagne,
一些非常贵的迷你小汉堡 由几个以为他们泡到姑娘的家伙付的钱
some seriously expensive sliders paid for by some guys who thought they'd pulled.
当晚你有没有在任何时间 离开过你的同伴
Were you away from your party at any point in the evening?
没有 我是说 我去过厕所 不过…
No. Well, I mean, I went to the loo, but…
-电话呢  -我可能给乔发了短信
-Phone calls? -I probably texted Joe.
你有我的电话 你可以查
You have my phone. You can check it.
你什么时候回到了酒店
What time did you return to the hotel?
我根本不记得
I have no idea.
我喝多了
I drank way too much.
我在夜总会离开了莫妮和她朋友 她直接去的机场
I left Mon and her friends at the club, and she went straight to the airport.
大约什么时候
Estimate.
我连回去的过程都不记得
I can't even remember getting back.
我知道我叫了辆德士 回到了我的房间
I know I got a cab, made it back to my room,
接下来我只记得我的闹铃响了
but the next thing I remember is my alarm going off,
到了该去机场的时间
saying it was time to go to the airport.
闭路电视监控没有你回到酒店的记录
There's no CCTV of you returning to the hotel.
我想有一个…边门
There was a side door, I think.
一个没有摄像头监控的边门
A side door not covered by a camera?
这么说你不相信我
So you don't believe me.
纽约这么远 而你只待了这么短时间
New York is a long way to go for such a short trip.
你一定明白这看起来有多奇怪
You must see how odd that looks.
我在告别单身之夜只想和我妹妹在一起
My sister is the only person I wanted to spend my hen night with.
这有什么奇怪 她是我最好的朋友
What's so odd about that? She's my best friend.
（到处都是娜塔的流言 恐怖主义 怎么回事 ）
（别傻了 当然不是）
-嘿 乔 -嘿 警察在这里
-Hey, Joe. -Hey. The police are here.
-发生了什么事  -我现在还不知道
-What's going on? -Well, I don't know yet.
我在给可能知道的人打电话 可大家都在睡觉
I'm calling people who might, but the world's asleep.
我的朋友们在酒店 我正要过去
My lot are at the hotel. I'm heading there now.
保持联系
You can just keep in touch.
如果听到什么消息给我电话 好吗  我也会这么做
Call me if you hear anything, okay? I'll do the same.
谢谢 莫妮
Thanks, Mon.
好吧
Okay.
你知道她做了什么吗
Do you know what she's done?
她什么都没做
She hasn't done anything.
我要不要告诉你我认为她做了什么
Should I tell you what I think she's done?
不用 请让一下
-No. Excuse me.
好
-Yeah.
莫妮克
Monique!
我就来 妈妈 等等
I'm coming, Mum! Wait!
（娜塔莉你在哪 我需要那笔钱）
（娜塔莉 你现在有麻烦了）
我时间不多了
I don't have long.
我们俩一样
That makes two of us.
爷爷 我不是跟你说过 不要睡觉的时候点着蜡烛吗
What have I told you about leaving candles burning when you go to sleep, Granda?
会有火灾风险
It's a fire risk.
我的眼睛几乎完全看不见了 把钱花在电灯上有什么意义
The sight's almost completely gone now. What's the point in spending on lights?
如果你看不见 蜡烛有什么意义
If you can't see, what's the point of a candle?
那我就完全放弃 是不是
I'll give up totally then, will I?
太冷了
It's freezing.
你应该好好照顾自己
You need to look after yourself.
什么食物都没有吗 这些快过期一年了
Is there no food at all? These are almost a year out of date.
我不吃罐头番茄
I won't eat tinned tomatoes.
你上次买了那些东西的时候我就说过了
I said that when you bought all that stuff the last time.
我很抱歉很久没来
I'm sorry I haven't been around.
有人问过我的下落吗 没人来过家里
Has anybody been asking about me? Nobody's been to the house?
只有你派来的那些多管闲事的家伙们
Only those nosy parkers you sent.
他们还在给你送饭吗
-They're still bringing you meals?
如果我让他们进来的话
-If I let them in.
我不用眼睛看就知道你在摇头 所以别摇了
And I don't need me eyes to know that you're shaking your head. So, stop it.
好吧 很好
Okay. Good.
你会惊讶于一名饥饿的士兵
You'd be amazed what a hungry soldier can do
能用一罐豆子和一点想象力做出什么
with a tin of beans and a bit of imagination.
你是个好孩子
You're a good boy.
我真希望能留下
I wish I could stay.
至少这次 我会告诉那些来寻找真相的人
Well, at least this time, I'd be telling whoever comes looking the truth
我最近没见过你
when I say that I haven't seen you.
肖恩 他们要来了 对不对
They are coming, Seany, aren't they?
莫妮克
Monique!
怎么了 妈妈
What's going on, Mum?
他们要把我们赶出去
They're throwing us out now.
没关系 别担心 你们要搜查 是吗
It's okay. Don't worry. You're doing a search, yeah?
-你是  -莫妮克汤普森 你呢
-And you are? -Monique Thompson. You?
到底搜查什么  我家娜塔莉呢
Searching for what, exactly? Where's my Natalie?
我来是为了执行搜查令 除此之外 我不能告诉你别的了
We're here to execute a search warrant. I can't tell you anything more than that.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我舅舅不舒服 他走开了
My uncle's not feeling well. He's wandered off.
-谁  -别担心
-Who has? -Don't worry.
-告诉特里送大家去酒店 -你不觉得应该把衣服换了吗
-Tell Terry to get everyone to the hotel. -Don't you think you should get changed?
-我没事 -穿件大衣
-I'm fine. -Put a coat on.
我说了我没事 妈妈
I said I'm fine, Mum.
你在隐瞒什么
What are you hiding?
无可奉告
No comment.
你在10点16分入住酒店后做了什么
What did you do after you checked into the hotel at 10:16
上周一上午
last Monday morning?
-无可奉告 -你问是否有什么地方
-No comment. -You asked if there was somewhere
你可以去一边工作一边等房间 阿德什 你得做什么工作
you could work until your room was ready. What work, Aadesh?
无可奉告
No comment.
是有关你和库珀纽曼的代表 会面的工作吗
Was it for the meeting you had with representatives of Cooper Newman?
毛遂自荐当网络安全顾问吗
To pitch yourself as a cybersecurity consultant?
无可奉告
No comment.
关于你要去哪里 你为什么对你的家人撒谎
Why did you lie to your family about where you were going?
无可奉告
No comment.
阿德什 你知道谁在经营 库珀纽曼公关公司吗
Do you know who runs Cooper Newman PR, Aadesh?
当然 她刚被提名为驻英国大使
Obviously. She's just been named ambassador to the UK.
乔普拉先生
-Mr. Chopra.
他也是里奥纽曼的母亲
-She's also Leo Newman's mother.
会面后你做了什么
What did you do after the meeting?
第二天凌晨2点你在做什么
What were you doing at 2:00 the following morning?
我告诉你我没在做什么 该死的绑架
I'll tell you what I wasn't doing. A bloody kidnapping!
乔普拉先生
Mr. Chopra.
你直到3点之后才入住
You didn't check in till after three o'clock.
我迟到了 坏习惯
I was running late. Bad habit.
给你安排的发言时间是几点
What time were you scheduled to speak?
会议3点开始 我应该在4点30上台
The conference started at 3:00. I was due onstage at 4:30.
-不想听其他的发言吗  -并不想
-Didn't want to hear other presentations? -Not really.
会议的确切性质是什么
What was the exact nature of the conference?
我肯定你已经知道了
I'm sure you already know that.
库珀纽曼基金会
The Cooper Newman Foundation
给世界各地的机构捐赠
gives money to institutions all over the world.
一些受益方的发言人
Speakers from some of the beneficiaries
介绍捐赠所资助的项目
talked about projects the donations made possible.
基本上是公司公关
It's basically corporate PR.
凯瑟琳纽曼和她的儿子里奥一直在场吗
And Katherine Newman was there throughout, with her son, Leo?
我猜是吧 我说过了 我错过了开头
I imagine so. As I said, I missed the opening.
塔拉 你为什么出席会议
Why were you there, Tara?
因为他们的捐赠 帮助学院建立了研究图书馆
Because their donation helped the college build a research library.
当然 但为什么选你去
Sure. But why choose you?
为什么不能选我
Why not me?
他们请你去的还是你自愿去的
Were you asked or did you volunteer?
我的同事们都有安排了 而我家里的情况比较…
All my colleagues had commitments, whereas my domestic situation is more…
复杂
complicated.
那么说你是自愿的
So, you volunteered?
是的
Yes.
你不情愿 和你在发言时表现出的一样
With the same reluctance you showed delivering your speech?
我有时差
I was jet-lagged.
现在还有
Still am.
你为什么没参加酒会和庆祝晚宴
Why didn't you attend the drinks and gala dinner?
答案是一样的 我在酒吧很快喝了一杯 帮助入眠
Same answer. I had a quick drink at the bar to help me sleep.
在酒吧和任何人交谈了吗
Talk to anyone at the bar?
和酒吧服务员闲聊了几句 除此之外 我不记得了
Passed the time of day with the barman. Apart from that, not that I recall.
然后就去睡觉了
Then I went to bed.
几点
What time?
大概9点30、10点
9:30, 10:00?
在那之后你离开过房间吗
Did you leave your room again after that?
其实离开过
Actually, yeah.
我睡不着
I couldn't sleep,
所以我想应该做平时在家做的事 我就…起床去散步
so I thought I'd do what I do at home, and I got up and walked.
你常常失眠吗
You often have trouble sleeping?
有时候
Sometimes.
不过散步似乎有助于让我的头脑平静
But walking seems to help calm my thoughts.
那是我想出解决方案的时候
It's when I work things out.
散步和地西泮
That and then Diazepam?
你们去过我家了
You've been in my house?
（北爱尔兰 班戈码头）
妮可拉
Nicola.
我正希望你在这里呢
I was hoping you'd be here.
肖恩 是你吗
Sean, is that you?
可以上吗
Permission to mount?
这…
Well…
正确的术语是“上船”
correct term is "board."
“上船”
"Board."
等等
Wait.
你是一个人 对吗
You're alone, right?
你觉得我为什么在这里
Why do you think I'm here?
来吧
Come on.
我们出海去
Let's get out on the water.
（蒂尔森 摩托车快递员仍昏迷）
（老人说“不要联系”）
我今晚会一直在这里吗
Am I gonna be here all night?
我明天应该去马尔代夫的
Meant to be going to the Maldives tomorrow.
或者是今天 我不…
Or today. Look…
几点了
What time is it?
我们在等什么
What are we waiting for?
在当今世界 人们似乎越来越难以
In a world in which it seems harder and harder
辨识任何事物的客观真理是什么
to recognize what the objective truth is about anything,
科学研究以及各种科研机构
scientific research, and the buildings housing it,
变得越来越神圣
become ever more sacred
同时确定性变得越来越稀有
as certainties become ever more scarce.
我代表大学感谢基金会
On behalf of the university, I'd like to thank the foundation.
那看上去不像有时差
That doesn't look like jet lag.
像是一个因为自己其实讨厌的礼物 不得不说感谢话的人
That looks like someone having to say thanks for a present they actually hate.
有什么好笑的
Something funny?
只是在想我女儿
Just thinking about my daughter.
不好笑 不
Not funny. No.
塔拉 你认识里奥纽曼吗
Do you know Leo Newman, Tara?
不认识
No, I don't.
从未见过
Never met him?
没见过
No.
但你知道他在你的大学就读 对吗
But you knew he was studying at the university, didn't you?
对吗
Didn't you?
-是的 -因为你抗议了
-Yes. -Because you protested
反对他的录取
against his admission.
我不确定“抗议”是正确的用词
I'm not sure if "protested" is the right word.
我质疑了在基金会的捐款和录取里奥之间
I questioned whether there was a link between the money from the foundation
是否有联系
and Leo being awarded a place.
看来你在校园里造成了不小的风波
Looks like you kicked up quite a fuss on campus.
而且你把它透露给了媒体
And you leaked it to the media.
这种事必须透明 否则大家都会受影响
These things have to be transparent, or everyone suffers.
然而你一定得罪了许多人
Still, you must have annoyed a lot of people.
包括你的上司
Including your bosses.
那是搞学术的地方
It's a place of learning.
人们相信为信念挺身而出的重要性
People see the importance of standing up for what you believe in.
你的信念是什么
Which is what, in your case?
择优录取
Meritocracy.
然后发生了什么
So, what happened?
学院进行了调查 他们没有发现不当行为的证据
There was a college investigation. They found no evidence of wrongdoing.
所以里奥被录取是应该的
So, Leo was there on merit?
是的
Yes.
-你肯定不认识他  -不认识
-And you definitely don't know him? -No.
这很奇怪 因为他好像认识你
That is strange, because he seems to know you.
我们的美国同事找到了里奥的笔记本电脑
Our colleagues in America recovered a laptop of Leo's
你的名字经常出现在他的课堂笔记里
on which your name appears regularly in his lecture notes.
我无法控制谁来听我的讲座
I have no control over who sits in on my lectures.
好吧 当我第一次提到他名字时 你为什么没有告诉我
Okay. Why didn't you tell me
你和里奥之间的联系
about your connection with Leo when I first mentioned his name?
我们没有“联系” 我只是提出了质疑
There is no "connection." I raised concerns.
他们调查了 是我错了
They were investigated. I was wrong.
你不觉得奇怪 在那么多人中 偏偏是你
And you don't think it looks odd that you should go
去向库珀纽曼致敬
and pay homage to Cooper Newman?
那都是过去的事了
It's old news.
我还有更重要的事要操心
I have more important things to worry about.
蓝色知更鸟控股公司
Blue Robin Holdings.
什么
What?
认识这个名字吗
Recognize the name?
-不 -我们在查看你的电脑
-No. -We're looking at computers
你家里和办公室的电脑
from your home and your workplace.
在你的个人电脑中存有 蓝色知更鸟控股公司的银行详情
You have Blue Robin Holdings bank details saved on your personal laptop.
看起来他们定期将存款打入
It seems they make regular deposits
一个注册地址在沃克斯豪尔的 公共建筑的帐户中
to an account registered at a public building in Vauxhall.
我对此一无所知 我得…
Don't know anything about that. I'll--
我得查一下
I'll have to look into it.
对 我们也会查
Yeah, so will we.
（欧文尼尔森来电）
喂
Hey.
斯科特 我没收到你的最新信息
I'm not seeing updates from you, Scott.
现在还没有太多信息 正在审讯嫌疑人
There's not a lot to say yet. The suspects are still being questioned.
显然不是你在讯问
Well, obviously not by you.
不是我 有一些司法管辖权的问题
No. There are some issues around jurisdiction.
真的吗
Really?
更大的问题是一个孩子在48小时前被劫持
There's a bigger issue around a kid that was snatched 48 hours ago,
我们还是不知道是谁干的或动机是什么
and we still have no idea who took him or why,
更不用说他现在在哪里 我的时间不多
let alone where he is right now. I don't have a lot of time here.
是的 我明白
Yeah, I understand that.
是吗
Do you?
你认为
How long do you think
地球上最大的传播机构的老板
the head of the biggest communications agency on the planet
能同意让她儿子被劫持这件事保密多久
is going to agree to keep her son's abduction quiet?
斯科特 网上刚披露了 行李箱里的孩子名叫里奥纽曼
The Internet just named Leo Newman as the kid in the suitcase, Scott.
这件事马上就要公开了
This thing's gonna break.
随时可能发生 到那一刻
It could be any minute now, and when it does,
我们没有任何线索这一事实
the fact that we have nothing
就不再是我们的问题 而会成为全球新闻
stops being our problem and becomes global news.
听着 我们在争取引渡吗
Listen, are we working on extradition?
当然
Of course.
很好
Good.
在你看来 这些人很有希望吗
These guys look good to you, right?
现在还难说
It's still kind of hard to tell.
到审讯室去 想尽一切办法 让他们交待地更容易些 好吗
Well, get in that room and do whatever it takes to make telling easier. Okay?
好吧 我会的
Okay. Will do.
我好想你
I've missed this.
是吗
Did you now?
等等
Wait.
你知道我喜欢什么
You know what I like.
这怎么样
How's that?
确保绑紧
Make sure it's tight.
就这样
That's it.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
肖恩
Sean. Sean!
（格林威治时间 凌晨2点25分）
绝对不行
Absolutely not.
可是我们没有时间了 里奥也是
Well, we're running out of time here, and so is Leo.
幸会 我叫斯科特安德森
Nice to meet you. Scott Anderson.
谢谢你协助我们 安德森特工
Thank you for assisting us, Agent Anderson.
你的联络工作应该有助于全方位沟通 我们进展如何
Your liaison should help communication all around. Where are we?
娜塔莉汤普森的财务安排需要进一步调查
Well, Natalie Thompson's financial arrangements need further scrutiny.
塔拉麦卡利斯特对库珀纽曼曾有不满
Tara McAllister had a grudge against Cooper Newman and Aadesh Chopra--
阿德什乔普拉决定“无可奉告” 这些我都看见了
Has elected to go "no comment." All of which I saw.
我没有看到的是证据
What I'm not seeing is evidence.
我们有足够的证据拘留他们吗
Do we have enough to hold them?
现在还不够 先生
Not yet, sir.
对不起 可是四名英国公民
Excuse me, but four British citizens
彼此住得相当近
living in pretty close proximity to each other
在那个酒店住了一晚 第二天乘飞机离开
spent one night at that hotel before flying out the next day.
其中至少有两个人和库珀纽曼有联系
At least two of them have links to Cooper Newman.
他在召开会议 一半的客人都和库珀有联系
Who were holding a conference. Half the guests had links to Cooper.
-他们在说谎 -你怎么知道
-They're lying. -How do you know that?
你能证明吗
Can you prove it?
多点时间 对他们施加更多压力 我认为能
Given some time, pushing them harder, I think so.
在如何审讯方面我不需要建议
I don't need advice on running an interrogation.
与此同时 肖恩蒂尔森在逃亡路上
Meanwhile, Sean Tilson is leaving a trail of destruction
让我们非常被动
on his way to wherever it is he's heading.
他是关键人物 和面具劫持者
He's the link between the gang in the masks and whoever has Leo.
和控制里奥的人有关 所以在纽约待了更久
That's why he stayed in New York.
我阻止这升级为相关的系列犯罪
The only way I'm stopping this escalating to a linked series crime
和令所有人头疼的局面的唯一办法
and a world of pain for all of us
就是我能保证我们就快抓住蒂尔森了
is my assurance that we're close to apprehending Tilson.
让我旁听 我会给他们施压
Let me sit in. I'll put them under some pressure.
你怎么会认为他们的回答会不一样
What makes you think their answers will be any different?
经验
Experience.
让他旁听 不过让凡妮莎提问题
Sit in. But leave the questions to Vanessa.
通力合作 我们需要结果
Work together on this. We need results.
他是谁
Who's this?
美国联邦调查局特工 斯科特安德森进入了审讯室
FBI Special Agent Scott Anderson enters the interview room.
你还在英国的司法管辖范围
You're still under UK jurisdiction,
安德森特工不会提问题
and Agent Anderson will not be asking questions.
为什么选麦迪逊公园酒店
Why the Park Madison?
我…想让一切都非常特别
I-- I wanted everything to be special.
你还在租房 对吗
You're still renting, aren't you?
40岁以下的人没人在伦敦买得起房子
Nobody under the age of 40 can afford to buy in London.
但不是所有人住豪华酒店 而同时去借高利贷
But not everybody stays in luxury hotels, yet also uses loan sharks.
如果你知道他 那你一定也知道 那些钱不是我借的
If you know about him, then you must also know it wasn't me who borrowed that money.
娜塔莉 你是从哪里弄来的现金还他
Where'd you get the cash to pay him, Natalie?
我…
Well, I…
-为了这趟旅行攒了好多年 -攒现金
-…put it aside for the trip for ages. -In cash?
现金 所以才是美元
In cash. That's why it was in dollars.
一旦开始打算结婚 就连杯酒都很少买
Once you say you're getting married, you hardly buy a drink,
莫妮说最好用信用卡购物 所以…
and Mon said it was best to shop on my credit cards, so…
对于一天来说 那可是好多钱
Still, it's a lot of money for one day.
我说过了 我想让一切很特别
Like I said, I wanted it to be special.
你在哪里换的钱
Where did you change the money?
-我不记得 -你一定有收据吧
-Can't remember. -You must have a receipt.
我会以为做你这种工作的人 总是保留详细的记录
I would have thought someone in your job always kept scrupulous records.
我也会以为做你这种工作的人 只会逮捕罪犯
And I would have thought someone in yours would only arrest criminals.
你本来去不起美国 是不是
You couldn't afford to go to America, could you?
实际上 你的银行记录说明 你几乎连伯明翰都去不起
Actually, your bank records suggest you could barely afford to go to Birmingham.
你告诉你妻子要去那里
Where you told your wife you were.
阿德什 你为什么住在这么贵的酒店
Why such an expensive hotel, Aadesh?
无可奉告
No comment.
你在干嘛 能不能别那样
What is that? Can he not do that?
-什么  -就是… 那样
-What? -The… That.
你听到了 对吧
You heard it right?
我们看了你给库珀纽曼的简历
We've been looking at the CV you gave to Cooper Newman,
你在其中对你的学业成就撒了谎
on which you lie about your academic achievements,
还有你的就业经历 你参与的慈善工作
your employment history, your involvement in charity work
还有你的居住情况
and your living arrangements.
看 他又那么做了 允许他那么做吗
He did it again. Is he allowed to do that?
你是个骗子 对吗 阿德什
You're a liar. Aren't you, Aadesh?
我们之前给你看了这个人的照片
This is the man whose photograph we showed you earlier.
两年前国际刑警组织 发出了逮捕他的红色通缉令
Interpol issued a Red Notice for his arrest two years ago.
他是一个很危险的人物
He's a very dangerous individual.
上周一 他用假名字 也入住了麦迪逊公园酒店
He also checked into the Park Madison last Monday, under a pseudonym.
下午5点15分 这是他在酒店大堂
Here he is in the lobby at 17:15.
晚上7点22分 这是他在酒店的酒吧
Here he is in the hotel bar at 19:22.
这是你
And here's you.
紧跟在他后面 进入男厕所
Going into the men's room, right after him.
-只不过你说：“从来没见过他” -我没看见他
-Only you said, "Never seen him before." -I didn't see him.
-拜托 乔普拉先生… -不
-Please, Mr. Chopra-- -No!
什么都不说让我看起来有罪
Saying nothing is making me look guilty.
我没看到他
I didn't see him.
-你跟他说话了吗  -说话 什么 在男厕所
-Did you talk to him? -Talk to him? What, in the gents?
在男厕所不能说话 尿尿的时候眼睛要看着天花板
You don't talk in the gents. You keep your eyes on the ceiling while you wazz.
你只有在甩的时候才向下看 不能左顾右盼
You look down to shake and keep your eyes in your lane.
不是吗
Innit?
你们完全没说话
You didn't speak at all?
-没有 -我肯定你是知道的
-No. -As I'm sure you're aware,
公共厕所里面没有闭路电视监控 所以除了你的话 我们没有其他证据
there's no CCTV in public bathrooms, so we only have your word for that.
阿德什 目前来看 你的话好像不可靠
And at this point, Aadesh, that seems less than reliable.
我没有说谎
I'm not lying.
-狗屎 -安德森特工
-Bullshit. -Agent Anderson.
他花了一整天查看场地 然后他们在男厕所交流了
He spent the whole day scoping the place, and then they debriefed in the men's room.
你不是说他不问问题吗
What happened to him not asking any questions?
那是指控
That was an accusation.
关于那次会面 库珀纽曼说了什么
What did Cooper Newman say about the meeting?
为什么问这个  你觉得他对我们说了什么
Why? What do you think they told us?
我只是想知道他们认为会面进行得如何
Just wondered how they thought it went.
现在他们不会给我打电话了 是不是
Don't suppose they're gonna call me now, are they?
没人敢这么对待我 肖恩 你听见了吗
No one does this to me, Sean! Do you hear me?
我不在乎他会不会知道我们的事
I don't care if he finds out about us.
我不在乎他跟我离婚 离也值了
I don't care if he divorces me. It'll be worth it.
这是该死的绑架
This is bloody kidnap!
会面之后你做了什么
What did you do after the meeting?
什么都没做 我叫了客房送餐 我睡觉了
Nothing. I got room service. I went to bed.
他第一次到地球上最棒的城市之一
His first trip to one of the greatest cities on Earth,
而他连酒店都没离开
and he doesn't leave the hotel.
我跟五个成年人住在 和这间屋子一样大的房子里 朋友
I live with five adults in a house the size of this room.
没有比睡觉更重要的
-Nothing beats sleep.
阿德什 你凌晨2点时在做什么
-What were you doing at 2:00 a.m.?
什么 没做什么
What? N-Nothing.
酒店记录显示你在凌晨1点43分 选择了一部付费电影
Hotel records show you selected an on-demand movie at 1:43 a.m.
《迈阿密辣妹》
Miami Spice.
你知道如果我想溜出去 我会做什么
You know what I'd do if I was gonna slip out,
知道以后得说服别人我在房间里
knowing I'd have to convince people sometime later that I was actually there?
在我离开之前 开始放一部电影
Right before I left, I'd start a movie.
我会想一定有某种我在看电影的记录
I'd figure there'd be some record of me watching.
你不会租一部色情片 对吗
-You wouldn't hire porn though, would you?
如果我像你一样 我就会
-If I looked like you, that's what I'd do.
你这话是什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
你记得《迈阿密辣妹》的情节吗
Do you remember the plot of Miami Spice?
其实我记得 我想你在里面
Yeah. I think you were in it.
-真好笑… -够了
-Oh, you know, it's funny-- -Okay!
我不是骗子
I am not a liar.
好吗 我不是骗子
All right? I am not a liar.
我假装比现实中更成功
I pretended to be more successful than I am
因为我即将跟世界上最大的传播机构开会
because I was meeting the world's top strategic communications agency,
我需要他们把我当回事
and I needed them to take me serious.
所以我才住那个酒店
That's why I stayed at that hotel.
所以你也没提到过你有犯罪记录吗
Is that why you also didn't mention you have a criminal record?
这怎么不是问题
How is that not a question?
我以为你不会问问题
I thought you weren't asking questions.
我一直很好奇这个袋子
Well, I just keep wondering about this bag.
什么袋子
What bag?
你留在水疗中心衣物柜的那个
The one you left in a locker at the spa.
然后在退房的时候他们提醒你 你在前台取回了
Then picked up at reception when they reminded you about it at checkout.
袋子里有什么东西
What was in it?
显然是洗漱用品
Toiletries. Obviously.
不是现金
Not cash?
-不是什么  -你没有留下一个袋子
-Not what? -You weren't leaving a bag
里面都是现金 好让其他人取走
full of cash for someone to pick up later?
你疯了吗
Are you mad?
你知道我是怎么想的吗
You know what I think?
我想你是钱
I think you're the money.
这种行动需要三个要素
Operation like this takes three things.
计划、懂技术和一定数额无法追踪的现金
Planning, tech savvy and a certain amount of untraceable cash.
你就是钱的部分
You're the money.
你满嘴狗屎
And you're full of shit.
我当时只是个孩子 那是一次警告
I was a kid. It was a caution.
我以为我一到18岁 记录就取消了
I thought it was spent once I was 18.
你骇入了英格兰和威尔士的考试委员会
You hacked the main examining board for England and Wales
把两次即将进行的A级试卷 给了你所有的朋友
and gave two upcoming A-level exam papers to all your mates,
导致试卷完全作废
making them completely unusable.
可是那时我承认了 我现在也承认
But I came clean then, and I'm coming clean now.
你承认是因为你被逮住了
You came clean because you got caught.
阿德什 我们的问题是 上周一晚上 有人在麦迪逊公园酒店
Our problem, Aadesh, is that someone at the Park Madison last Monday night
有技术能力关闭并控制闭路电视监控系统
had the expertise to disable and then override CCTV
在15层 长达11分钟
on the 15th floor for 11 minutes.
他们给劫持录了像 然后在同一时间
They recorded the abduction and then released it simultaneously
从一批看似无法追踪的代理电子邮件帐户 发布了视频
from a batch of seemingly untraceable proxy email accounts.
并不是人人都会这样的技术
Not everybody has the know-how to make that happen.
-可是有很多人会 -是的 包括你
-But plenty do. -Yeah, including you.
对 可我没做
Yeah, but I didn't!
我… 我说了谎 因为我需要一个机会
I-- I lied 'cause I need a break.
就…
Just…
我想做父亲
I wanna be a dad.
我想自己创业 养活我的家人
I wanna build a business of my own. Take care of my family.
我只想做到这些
That is all I care about.
够了
Oh, pack it in.
（北爱尔兰）
-我们跟史蒂夫谈了 -黛西没事吧
-We spoke to Steve. -Is Daisy okay?
-她知道发生了什么吗  -他说你们结婚这么多年
-Does she know what's going on? -He says in your years together,
他从来不知道 你会在失眠的夜晚起来去散步
he never once knew you to get up and walk during a sleepless night.
他在说谎
He's lying.
我们正在办离婚 为了伤害我 史蒂夫什么都做得出、说得出
We're going through a divorce, and Steve will do and say anything to damage me.
-可他已经获得监护权了 -不 他获得了暂时监护权
-But he's already got custody. -No, he got temporary custody.
在我们那里 父亲得到子女监护权是相当少见的
Where I'm from, it's unusual for the father to get the kid.
也许在你们那里
Maybe where you're from
他们对想要有事业的女性 持有更开明的看法
they have a more enlightened view of women who want careers.
在马里兰州
In Maryland?
不太可能
Not so much.
史蒂夫也有事业
Steve has a career too.
-不 史蒂夫有一份工作 -他挣钱比你多
-Steve has a job. -He earns more than you.
大多数人挣钱都比我多 但钱从来不是他的不安全感的根源
Most people earn more than me, but money was never the source of his insecurity.
是学识
That's intellectual.
很多男人对能看穿自己的女性感到不舒服
Lots of men aren't comfortable with women who know what they think.
在离婚申诉中史蒂夫提到“工作时间长
In the divorce petition, Steve cites "long hours,
酗酒、其他男人的短信
binge drinking, text messages from other men,
各种古怪行为的累积对婚姻造成了伤害
an accumulation of erratic behavior which proved deleterious to the marriage
让她变成不称职的母亲”
and her responsibilities as a parent."
他想伤害我
He wants to hurt me.
他知道黛西是他最有效的武器
And he knows Daisy is his most effective weapon.
（天啊 黛 你妈怎么了 为什么 ）
（牛津大学讲师在课堂上被捕）
（不是她 是的 说是“麦卡利斯特”）
（有影片 看…）
我从来没有忽视过她 我所做的一切都是为了她
I'd never neglect her. Everything I do is for her.
（你妈妈是罪犯吗 ）
（闭嘴）
（她会蹲监狱吗 不 是个误会）
（黛西 她做了什么 ）
嘿 总会发生变化
Hey, things change, you know?
你和史蒂夫当初一定自己还是孩子
You and Steve must have been almost kids yourselves.
你们犯了一个错误 突然就为人父母了
You make one mistake. Suddenly, you're a parent.
不许你把我的孩子称为错误
Don't you ever refer to my child as a mistake.
你从婚姻破裂以来 跟其他人约会过吗
Have you been seeing anyone since your marriage broke down?
没有认真的 我看不出这跟…
Nobody serious. I don't see what that's got--
你去哪里找“不是认真的人”
Where do you go to find "nobody serious"?
-你有我的手机 我用一个软件 -用得很频繁
-You've got my phone. I use an app. -Quite regularly.
如果我是男的 我们还会进行这种对话吗
Would we be having this conversation if I was a man?
你上一次使用是什么时候
When was the last time you used it?
你在麦迪逊公园酒店用过吗
Did you use it at the Park Madison?
你说你没有时间可以浪费
You said you had no time to waste.
-塔拉 你用了吗  -说一个生命危在旦夕
-Did you, Tara? -That a life is at risk.
-你用了吗  -我也许查看过
-Did you use it? -I might have checked it.
我查看了 但是我没用它
I did. But no, I didn't use it.
你没用它找性伴侣  还是你没用它跟人沟通
You didn't use it for sex? Or you didn't use it to communicate with another party?
我…不明白你的意思
I-- I don't understand.
端对端加密让那个平台
End-to-end encryption makes that particular platform
成为一种伪装沟通的有效方法 其实跟性毫无关系
an effective way to disguise communication that actually has nothing to do with sex.
对吗
Doesn't it?
我对此一无所知
I have no idea.
我只对性感兴趣
I'm all about the sex.
（默西塞德郡 高镇）
（你的小心脏砰砰跳）
（我想要你的肝脏放在盘子上）
你没事吧 朋友
You all right, mate?
（地点047 高镇 摄像头002）
（格林威治时间早6点19分）
你在30分钟后离开
You're leaving in 30 minutes.
除非你告诉我要把我带到哪里 我哪儿也不去
I'm not going anywhere until you tell me where you're taking me.
什么…真的吗
What-- For real?
你的手机和在搜查中查获的东西 会留在我们这里
Your phone and anything taken in the searches will stay with us.
有问题吗
Any questions?
好吧
Okay.
（第一区走廊）
（国家打击犯罪署）
你真的要这么做吗
You're really gonna do this?
这是我的决定
It's my decision.
你要放了他们
You're setting 'em free?
不是
No.
德士
Taxi!
他们没有获得自由
They're not free.
如果其中有人或所有人涉及劫持 他们会犯错的
If any or all of them are involved, they'll trip up.
等他们犯错的时候 会在我们的监视下
And when they do, we'll be watching.
（闭路电视摄像头运行中）
（闭路电视监控实况 木街爱巷）
（闭路电视监控实况）
（警察局 阿德什乔普拉）
（伦敦公交87号巴士线路）
（警告：闭路电视监控运行中）
（免费现金提取）
（闭路电视监控实况 木街分行）
（伦敦公交 德士）
（闭路电视监控 黑色德士）
（娜塔莉汤普森 黑色德士）
他说得对 你应该停止这个坏习惯
He's right, you know. You really do need to stop doing that.
（塔拉麦卡利斯特 娜塔莉汤普森、阿德什乔普拉）
（伦敦 莱姆豪斯）
（华盛顿特区）
谢谢 我们还有几个
Thank you. We also have confirmation hearings
总统的大使提名人的确认听证
on the president's nominations for several ambassadorial positions.
在我们讨论提名人名单之前
Before we go through the list of the nominees,
我应该确认我们暂时推迟了
I should confirm that we have postponed the hearing
凯瑟琳纽曼担任英国大使的确认听证
on the UK placement of Katherine Newman for the time being.
好的 我现在有请来自加州的
Okay, I'm going to hand over to the committee member
委员会成员发言
from California right now.
谢谢参议员 晚上好
Thank you, Senator. And good evening.
我想感谢…这…
I'd like to thank… the…
凯瑟琳 说出真相
Tell the truth, Katherine,
否则你的儿子将在全世界的注视下死去
or your son dies with the whole world watching.
说出真相
Tell the truth.
（说出真相）
字幕翻译：陈晓清